A Guide to the Virginius Dabney Papers 1949-[1967]
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Virginius Dabney Papers, 1949-[1967]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7690-k
This holding consists of 17 boxes of material.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This holding was acquired as a gift on October 18, 1969.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Virginius Dabney contain extensive correspondence carried on by Dabney as editor of the Richmond Times-Dispatch, in his personal life, and as a Pulitzer Prize- winning author. Other materials deal with his books such as Below the Potomac, The Dry Messiah, and Liberalism in the South, and much useful material collected as research material for these books is present. There is extensive material on the American Society of Newspaper Editors which Dabney served in various capacities including president. A great deal of useful material on race relations, African Americans, the N.A.A.C.P., etc., is present. Recent political history of Virginia is strongly represented in Dabney's correspondence as editor of Virginia's leading newspaper, and in his personal correspondence with figures such as Senator A. Willis Robinson, Francis Pickens Miller, and Senator Carter Glass.
Contents List
- A (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 1)
- A (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 1)
- Am-B (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 2)
- Be-C (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 3)
- Ch-D (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 4)
- Do-Fl (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 5)
- G-H (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 6)
- He-J (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 7)
- K-Mar (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 8)
- Mc-N (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 9)
- O-Q(Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 10)
- R-S (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 11)
- Sch-St (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 12)
- T-W (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 13)
- We-Z (Correspondence) 1949-1958 (Box 14)
- McNeil, Robert H. (Box 14)
- Colburn, John H. (Box 14)
- Eisenhower--Reprints, editorials, and letters (Box 14)
- Governor's Conference on Education [1966-1967] (Box 15)
- [Education] (Box 16)
- English Speaking Union (Box 16)
- Football (Box 16)
- Grits Controversy (Box 17)
- Ham Controversy (Box 17)
- International House, New Orleans (Box 17)
- Saturday Evening Post article: Segregation (Box 17)
- Speaking Engagements (Box 17)
- Virginia Council of Health and Medical Care (Box 17)
- Virginia Creepers (Box 17)